# 哈喽
Hello
# 自从过年之后 雪鱼就没有出去过
I haven’t gone out since the lunar new year
# 然后在家呢 就是
Staying at home
# 最近 确实是很长时间没有更新了
And it’s been a while since my last upload
# 和大家分享一下
I’m going to share with you
# 我有的时候喜欢
Sometimes I like
# 别出心裁做的一些食物
To cook food out of the ordinary
# 趁着打豆浆的时候呢 我们接下来要准备
While making the soybean milk, we are going to prepare
# 下一道菜的食材
The ingredients for the next dish
# 我呢 已经把肉切成了大块儿
I have chopped the meat into big chunks
# 这边切好了葱姜（没有蒜）
Here are cut scallions and ginger (without garlic)
# 把肉馅放在搅拌机里 搅拌起来
Put the ground meat into the blender, starts to mix
# 调肉馅 我倒是没有什么样的心得
I don’t have special experience with concocting grand meat
# 简单来说就是 去腥 加料酒 加葱姜
Put it simply, add Chinese cooking wine, add scallions and ginger to get rid of blood odor
# 然后呢 是调味 加盐 加花椒粉
Then, add salt and Sichuan peppercorn powder to improve the flavor
# 不要忘了 拿油滋润一下肉馅
Don’t forget to moisturize the ground meat with oil
# 快搅拌好的时候 我会在里面加一些香菜
I will add some cilantro when it’s almost well mixed
# 因为香菜再不吃 它就老了
Because if I don’t eat them now, they will be too old to enjoy
# 戴上我的一次性手套
Put on my disposable gloves
# 然后在锅里
Then, in the pot...
# 然后在锅...
Then the pot...
# 然后在这上面 锅里抹点油
Then on top of that, wipe the steamer pot with some oil
# 把丸子挤成一个稍微圆的形状
Squeeze the meat into the shape of the ball
# 放进里面就可以了
Then put the meatball in there
# 我也不知道能够挤多大
I don’t know how big I can squeeze
# 上面呢 我是蒸了自己的饭
On top of that, I’m going to steam some rice
# 不要问我 为什么不把它放下面
Don’t ask me why I don’t put it underneath
# 因为它这个碗有点大
Because this bowl is relatively big
# 如果放下面一层 放不进去
It can’t fit underneath
# 这样就可以了
This is fine
# 开火
Start cooking
# 水开后 二三十分钟就可以吃了
20-30 minutes after the water starts to boil, it’s ready to be eaten
# 今天中午呢 吃的就是凉拌土豆丝
For today’s lunch, I’m going to eat shredded potato salad
# 这个就是自己想的
This is my idea
# 因为早上起来 我是吃的黄金炒饭
Because this morning, I ate golden fried rice
# 剩下的蛋白 把它和虾仁 胡萝卜一起炒
Stir fry the remaining egg white with shrimp and carrots
# 还有呢 就是我们今天的重头戏
And, this is today’s star dish
# 蒸了20多分钟的肉丸子
Meatballs which has been steamed for over 20 minutes
# 开动开动了
I’m going to eat now
# 休息了这么久 其实也会想
After taking a long break, it comes to mind that
# 除了继续到各地去吃好吃的
Besides continue to have delicious food from different places
# 可能也会做一些其它的视频 比如说
Maybe I will make some other videos, for example
# 比如说 自己的一个小心愿
For example, my little wish
# 开家小餐饮店 或者说 它只是一个外卖店
Is to open a small restaurant, or it’s just a take-out restaurant
# 也是很开心的
I would be happy
# 好吧 走一步算一步
OK, one step at a time
# 今天的视频就到这儿 ( ^_^ )/~~拜拜
It’s pretty much for today’s video. See you
# 关 注
雪 鱼 探 店
# Subscribe